<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Maxwel Coura Oliveira</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Maxwel Coura Oliveira</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Maxwel Coura Oliveira</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Questionário (Survey) - O Manejo de Culturas e Plantas Daninhas no Brasil</title>
      <link>/post/2018-03-28-question%C3%A1rio-a-survey-manejo-de-planta-daninha-no-brasil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-03-28-question%C3%A1rio-a-survey-manejo-de-planta-daninha-no-brasil/</guid>
      <description>Quem somos nós? Eu sou Pesquisador Associado (pós-doc) na Universidade de Wisconsin-Madison, EUA, trabalhando com manejo de plantas daninhas junto com o Professor Assistente Rodrigo Werle.
O desafio no manejo de plantas daninhas Nos EUA, o manejo de plantas daninhas resistentes à herbicidas tornou-se um dos principais desafios para a produção agrícola. Junto dos EUA, o Brasil é um dos principais produtores de soja, milho e algodão no mundo. Porém, tem sido reportado o cresimento alarmante no número de plantas daninhas resistentes à herbicidas no Brasil (existem 46 casos únicos de planta daninha resistentes, sendo 8 plantas daninhas resistentes ao herbicida glifosato).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging: a new power of R-studio</title>
      <link>/post/2018-first-post-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-first-post-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2007, I downloaded R for the first time during a statistical class in my BSc degree. However, I did not see much necessity of R and the interface was not friendly. At that time, I had no idea about the power of R and R-studio software. When I joined the University of Nebraska-Lincoln in 2014, I took statistics class that used SAS as standard software. With SAS, I liked using for ANOVA, but I found challenging to conduct quantitative data analysis and plotting regression curves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>